Franz Boas’s description of Inuit life in the 19th century illustrates the probable moral code of early humans.
弗朗茨·博厄斯对19世纪因纽特人生活的描述，说明了早期人类很可能遵循的道德准则。
Here, norms were unwritten and rarely expressed clearly, but were well understood and taken to heart.
在因纽特人的社会里，规范是不成文的，也很少被明确地表达出来，但人们都很清楚这些规范，并将其铭记于心。
Dishonest and violent behaviours were disapproved of; leadership, marriage and interactions with other groups were loosely governed by traditions.
不诚实和暴力的行为不被认可；领导方式、婚姻以及与其他群体的交往，都由传统加以约束，但约束并不严格。
Conflict was often resolved in musical battles.
冲突常常在音乐对决中得到化解。
Because arguing angrily leads to chaos, it was strongly discouraged.
由于怒气冲冲地争吵会导致混乱，这种做法受到强烈反对。
With life in unforgiving northern Canada being so demanding, the Inuit’s practical approach to morality made good sense.
在严酷的加拿大北部，生活如此艰难，因纽特人以务实的态度对待道德，也就很有道理了。
The similarity of moral virtues across cultures is striking, even though the relative ranking of the virtues may vary with a social group’s history and environment.
不同文化中的道德美德惊人地相似，尽管这些美德的相对排序可能因社会群体的历史和环境而有所不同。
Typically, cruelty and cheating are discouraged, while cooperation, humbleness and courage are praised.
通常，残忍和欺骗会遭到反对，而合作、谦逊和勇气则受到赞扬。
These universal norms far pre-date the concept of any moralising religion or written law.
这些普遍的规范远在任何宣扬道德的宗教或成文法的概念出现之前就已存在。
Instead, they are rooted in the similarity of basic human needs and our shared mechanisms for learning and problem solving.
它们其实根植于人类基本需求的相似性，以及我们共有的学习和解决问题的机制。
Our social instincts include the intense desire to belong.
我们的社会本能包括对归属感的强烈渴望。
The approval of others is rewarding, while their disapproval is strongly disliked.
得到他人的认可令人满足，而遭到他人的否定则让人非常反感。
These social emotions prepare our brains to shape our behaviour according to the norms and values of our family and our community.
这些社会情感使我们的大脑做好准备，依照家庭和群体的规范与价值观来塑造我们的行为。
More generally, social instincts motivate us to learn how to behave in a socially complex world.
更广泛地说，社会本能促使我们去学习如何在社会关系复杂的世界里为人处世。
The mechanism involves a repurposed reward system originally used to develop habits important for self-care.
这一机制涉及一个被改作他用的奖励系统，它最初用于养成对自我照料很重要的习惯。
Our brains use the system to acquire behavioural patterns regarding safe routes home, efficient food gathering and dangers to avoid.
我们的大脑利用这一系统，习得关于安全的回家路线、高效采集食物以及需要避开的危险等方面的行为模式。
Good habits save time, energy and sometimes your life.
好习惯能节省时间和精力，有时还能救你一命。
Good social habits do something similar in a social context.
良好的社会习惯在社会环境中也起着类似的作用。
We learn to tell the truth, even when lying is self-serving; we help a grandparent even when it is inconvenient.
我们学会说真话，即使撒谎对自己有利；我们帮助祖父母，即使这样做并不方便。
We acquire what we call a sense of right and wrong.
我们习得了所谓的是非观。
Social benefits are accompanied by social demands: we must get along, but not put up with too much.
社会层面的好处伴随着社会层面的要求：我们必须与人和睦相处，但也不能一味忍让。
Hence self-discipline is advantageous.
因此，自律是有益的。
In humans, a greatly enlarged brain boosts self-control, just as it boosts problem-solving skills in the social as well as the physical world.
人类的大脑大幅增大，增强了自控能力，正如它也增强了人们在社会世界以及物质世界中解决问题的能力一样。
These abilities are strengthened by our capacity for language, which allows social practices to develop in extremely unobvious ways.
这些能力因我们的语言能力而得到强化，语言能力使社会习俗能够以极难察觉的方式发展。